Guide to the Stanford University Undergraduate Research Awards Nominee theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Undergraduate Research Award Nominee theses
2012-2013
SC1191
1 Linear feet (2 boxes)
Collection includes honors theses and research projects nominated for three undergraduate research awards including the Firestone Medals for Excellence in Undergraduate Research, the Robert M. Golden Medals for Excellence in Humanities and Creative Arts, and the David M. Kennedy Honors Thesis Prizes.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Biographical/Historical note
The Firestone Medals for Excellence in Undergraduate Research recognizes graduating seniors nominated by their academic programs or departments for undertaking honors projects in engineering and the social, physical and natural sciences.
The Robert M. Golden Medals for Excellence in Humanities and Creative Arts recognizes students completing honors projects in the humanities or creative projects in the fine arts. The Golden Medal is awarded to the top ten percent of all honors theses in the humanities, senior projects or performance in the arts.
The Kenedy prize is given annually for outstanding honors theses in the humanities, social sciences, natural sciences and engineering. Recipients of this award have accomplished significantly advanced research in the field and have demonstrated strong potential for publication in peer-reviewed scholarly works. The prize was established in recognition of David M. Kennedy, professor emeritus of history, and faculty co-director of Stanford's Bill Lane Center for the American West, and his longstanding commitment to mentoring undergraduate writers.
Text excerpted from:
https://undergrad.stanford.edu/opportunities-research/awards-and-graduation-honors/golden-firestone-and-kennedy-thesis-awards
http://news.stanford.edu/news/2013/june/graduating-senior-awards-062513.html
Scope and Contents
Collection includes honors theses and research projects nominated for three undergraduate research awards including the Firestone Medals for Excellence in Undergraduate Research, the Robert M. Golden Medals for Excellence in Humanities and Creative Arts, and the David M. Kennedy Honors Thesis Prizes.
Access Terms
Undergraduate Research Programs.; David M. Kennedy Honors Thesis Prize; Firestone Medals for Excellence in Undergraduate Research; Robert M. Golden Medals for Excellence in Humanities and Creative Arts; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Nominated theses and honors projects, Accn ARCH.2014-047
  - 2012 Nominees
    - Bennet, Brittany, Elegy. (Golden), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bleaman, Isaac, Vernacularity and authenticity in Sholem Aleichem's monologues: A variationist approach. (Golden), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chan, Stephanie, The Waizhou Special: Exploring the effects of immigrant diffusion on Chinese restaurant workers in McMinnville, Tennessee. (Firestone, Kennedy), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clark, Alexandra, Compassion at play: Cultivating compassion through theater with the fourth and fifth graders of Costano Elementary School. (Kennedy), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dang, Vanessa Marie, Glutamine metabolism is a compenent of MYC associated oncogene addiction in renal adenocarcinoma. (Kennedy, Firestone), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Feehan, Ross, Helping those who harm: Harmonizing the practice of ethics and aquaculture insurance in China. (Firestone), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Gray, Colin, Responding to the monetary superpower: investigating the behavioral spillovers of U.S. monetary policy. (Kennedy, Firestone), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Holtzman, Alexander, The unanticipated inequalities of electoral reform: Racial and ethnic disparities in voting behavior under Oakland's ranked choice voting program. (Firestone), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ibarra, Daniel Enrique, An assessment of late Pleistocene to Middle Holocene lake level fluctuations in Surprise Valley, California. (Kennedy, Firestone), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Kotzin, Jonathan J., The role of CD4+ T cells in the development of protective immunity to 2009 pandemic H1N1 influenza. (Kennedy, Firestone), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Nichols, Samara, Does infant directed speech facilitate familiar word recognition by 14- to 15-month olds? (Golden), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Poland, Susannah, The secret lives of beads: tracing the histories of beaded body adornment among the Chagga people of northern Tanzania. (Firestone), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Reid, Otis, Monitoring, expropriating, and interfering: concentrated ownership, government holdings, and firm value on the Ghana Stock Exchange. (Kennedy), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Tuan, Eric, Beyond cadence: post-cadential extensions and Josquin's compositional style. (Golden), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Weber, Sadie, Assessing the role of wild plant taxa in predomestication cultivation during the pre pottery Neolithic A. (Firestone, Golden, Kennedy), 2012 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 2013 nominees
    - Katsma, Holst, Problems of loudness in the novel. (Golden, Kennedy), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Knudson, Elizabeth, National and ethnic identity in Africa. (Firestone), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Kramer, Anne Devon, A L'Aube de l'Age Atomique, "Entre L'Enfer et La Raison." (Kennedy), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Radcliffe, Ben, Texture, practice, type scene: A stuy of iconicity in Homeric sacrifice. (Golden), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Sapp, Richie, Acutely disrupting the function of PirB enhances ocular dominance plasticity. (Firestone, Kennedy), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Shelley-Abrahamson, Seth, Hopf modules and representations of finite groups of lie type. (Firestone), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Trugman, Daniel T., A pseudo-dynamic rupture model generator for earthquakes on geometrically complex faults. (Firestone, Golden, Kennedy), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Vaid-Menon, Alok, Rainbows are just refracted white light: settler homonationalism in Neo-Apartheid. South Africa (Golden), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 8)